what a masterpiece yeah right beautiful
the stars have aligned like it's amazing
that's how it always feels you know with
these things it's like wow look at this
you know alignment phenomenal
game
[Music]
alrighty man how you doing yo yo yo
what's up dude
how are you pretty good I'm I'm actually
feeling extra good right now ask me why
okay why because your boy just found a
new subdomain takeover zero day right
before this call and yeah I got I got my
homies scanning for it they're popping
left and right I don't even do SUB
domain takeovers anymore but I just
recently got back into the game just
because I saw this asset that looked
like it was going to be possible so
nice I'm pretty hype it it you know I
talk about the Recon game being a bit of
a grind you know like doing really wide
Recon always having to update your tools
always having to uh you know increase
the speed air efficiency of your tools
to compete with other people but man
does it feel good when you just like
pop something and you just see like boom
boom boom boom boom ah that's awesome so
is this like a whole new like uh like
class or like a whole service or is like
a like you know like shop yeah it's a
new service
um it's not you know I say zero day and
it is a zero day but it's it's not you
know it's not something Mega technical
it's just a new service that there's not
any documentation on
um you know this service being able to
be subdomain taken over subdomain
takeover'd turn that into a verb for you
um so I was pretty excited about it it
was really easy
um but yeah I think people just don't
think about it from A New Perspective
anymore a lot of times people will just
Google hey can I do something to take
over on Bloody blah and then just stop
there if there's no results but really
you got to go pay like we always say man
you got to go pay the the entrance fee
to get access to the control panel to
see if you can register the domain
yourself and a lot of times you'll take
an l and you won't and you'll pay that
you know 50 bucks or whatever it was to
get access to that service but the other
times you know stuff will pop in it and
it's great nice well that's awesome dude
that that's I mean that's just you know
showing that the stuff we talk about
like it's here it is being used in the
real world it works man it works
all right awesome let's see what we got
um so news as far as news goes once
again we've got a pretty good lineup
today
um this episode's probably going to be a
little bit light Joel and I both have
some extra stuff going on this week but
um we do have a decent amount of new
stuff so let's uh let's take a peek at
that yeah cool so the first thing that
came up was from um uh an operator no
operator oh boy yeah an operator so
um I don't know you know you may have
heard but there was a new TLD that was
released the dot zip TLD so oh yeah that
caused a whole thing on Twitter yeah so
Google if you don't know Google owns a
lot of different tlds
um I think honestly I think it's just
like one of their Hobbies they just
collect clps so that you know did you
know they own dot new as well so like
really yeah so you can go to docs.new or
sheets.new or slides.new and it makes it
no way yeah yeah it makes like a new
Google doc Google Sheets what you know
file or whatever yeah so like what the
heck
I don't even remember how I found that
at one point but like yeah so you can do
like docs.new that's like one of my
favorite ones that I use to like make
new documents and stuff that's awesome
but they also own dot zip you know they
own.google anyways so I feel like that's
kind of a sea surf though like I can
just create a bunch of new documents by
making a request to docs.u yeah docs.new
oh no wait did that like hold on hold on
did that just like stick it in my Google
Drive
yeah
what but I think google.com you could
have like anonymous
well it won't auto save until you put
something in it I think okay okay okay
but uh because if you could just like
have someone come to your page
window.open docs.new like 50 times
instantly and just blow up their Google
Drive that would be real Annoying it
wouldn't necessarily be hold in real
time yeah but like it would be annoying
yeah yeah so it's super interesting
um but yeah they own dot zip as well
like this the this dot TLD
um or this TLD and they released it to
the public so you can register domains
on the dot zip uh subdomain or okay I'm
sorry you still got me on the drive no
yes yeah so so okay so I'm sorry
continue you're saying the dot Zips they
they have dot zip now yeah yeah yeah so
now you can you can you know my
domain.zip and the you know the observed
listener can probably already see where
this is going because dot zip is
for zip files it's a very commonly used
file extension out in the wild
um so you can see the potential for
tricking people into visiting a domain
or having it at the end of a command or
something and so an operator put
together this awesome like basically a
proof of concept that shows okay like
imagine I send you this uh command this
wget command you know it just downloads
like a zip from the GitHub releases and
then it unzips it and in the screenshot
that they show it's downloading like the
zip it looks all completely normal you
unzip it and it's got their pwned
content in there and it took me like a
really long time to figure out how this
worked same man I commented on that and
I was like hey man what the heck is
going on and he he got me confused with
like the way that his like because he
posted a command that has of Ls right at
the end and it got me all hecked up
because I I couldn't read it because the
columns were switched around from normal
LS because he's using something weird
but I to be honest man like I don't know
I kind of thought everybody was
overreacting when this came out and and
you know at the end to be fair it's not
the biggest deal in the whole world but
um
definitely
you know when I clicked on operator's
post here
um and you scroll down here on I don't
it I think it's in the dark hold on yeah
it's it's uh yeah it's the second no I'm
gonna put it in the dark for you real
quick so you can see what I'm talking
about
um it's this so go to that post and then
scroll down to
um the the stack overflow uh image in
that post so if you go to an operator's
post there's a stack Overflow image and
I would absolutely just go to that wget
double click on it and then paste it
into my terminal and press enter yeah I
mean 100 like it's it's extremely like
it looks like very like you know like it
it doesn't look malicious at all it just
looks like any other like set of
commands or whatever that you would copy
and paste from like from like a stack
Overflow post right yeah I really like
the the breakdown that he did a little
bit later too where he actually breaks
it out and says okay the first you know
just that by adding a space here we're
able to skip that whole GitHub section
and then just make Source code.zip the
thing that he reaches out to yeah so
yeah so yeah you basically yeah what you
just talked about there is like kind of
like the little secret so in the
screenshot it's not obvious at all like
even in the original like tweet that
they made you don't really like
understand just because of the way that
the line wraps around the terminal and
stuff there's actually a space after the
like the one URL and Then followed by
like he owns source code.zip source Dash
code.zip right and so like you would
expect that this would download
source.zip but what you don't realize is
there's a space and it's actually two
different URLs and since source code.zip
is a valid domain now it resolves it and
then it it like downloads it and so
you could just see like it's literally
like one space difference right like are
you out of space and you and your your
opponed so sneaky man yeah and then I
bet I bet you could actually also sort
of
um combine this with a uh a sort of uh
what is it called is it zip slip because
this is a zip snip but maybe yeah dip
you can combine it with a zip slip
attack which I think is like a patch
reversal in the zip files right yeah um
and then you could get arbitrary file
right potentially so there's definitely
there's definitely some risk here I
wouldn't I don't know that I would go so
far as I mean we'll see how far how the
adoption goes but I don't know that I
would be I would go so far as to just
block the whole TLD yeah um but you know
hey maybe maybe that's the best move and
make sure that because at the end of the
day the big risk here is for technical
people making mistakes right it's not a
lot of times that
um non-technical people are running wget
and stuff like that so it's a it's a
little bit on the On The Fringe I would
say still take some user interactions
some social engineering but definitely
you know maybe not the best move from a
security perspective yeah and I was
thinking like maybe one of the the more
realistic use cases for like the Bounty
side is this is probably going to come
into play around like regex bypasses URL
like format or host checks and stuff
like that where maybe they're you know
inserting just enough file name or or
like at the file name portion of a URL
and you could somehow terminate the URL
and just turn it into a valid domain
that you own or pass a regex check that
is making sure it ends in dot zip or
something right like where normally this
would be impossible but now you can have
a domain and get a redirect or something
so yeah I think there are there are some
creative use cases and it's just one of
those things to maybe note down in in
your brain in the in your giant brain
database that like okay exactly this is
the thing that exists maybe maybe I'll
pull on that later yeah for sure I mean
in and yeah like Sammy we could even use
it for like uh like almost like a link
hijacking thing too if somewhere in like
a a flow of uh you know like a CI chain
or something like that there could be
someone accidentally putting a space and
now
you know between the zip file and now
you can just register that domain in the
boom so yeah we're like converting
relative URL to like a full domain or
something like that yeah that would be
really cool
sweet all right let's see what's the
next one we got oh okay I can talk talk
about this one so the next one that I
want to talk about was
um this post from uh if secure I'm not
even going to try to say his his real
name Ivan is his first name
fried trick Ivan fratric if secure and
this is actually from May uh 11 so
actually yeah this is still in this
episode's uh sort of period but it was
recently disclosed that he found a bunch
of bugs in sip um which I think is a
really cool protocol and I think is one
of the easiest protocols
um to sort of go after as an HTTP Bug
Hunter
um you can if you go after
um sip it's very similar to http in a
lot of ways
um I found some bugs in this protocol
I had a previous live hacking event and
it was a lot of fun so definitely want
to encourage people to go there read
read through these cves and these are
actually really really simple bugs too I
mean like you said in the tweet in the
subtweet
um one of them is is literally just like
a you could fit it into a tweet it's
just like you know sip slash 2.0 AAA Foo
and that gets misparsed and caused the
buffer overflow yeah worth noting you
could fit it in a tweet without a
Twitter blue subscription yeah ah there
you go you could put anything in a tweet
yeah but nowadays oh that's sad
um but yeah so definitely definitely
something to check out and I also I'm
just personally looking forward to the
next opportunity I get the next excuse I
get to audit some C code directly
um and look at you know these sort of
vulnerabilities because that's not
something I'm comfortable doing and
something I've done not something I've
done in the past um Beyond you know
rudimentary stuff
so I think taking a protocol that
something that I'm familiar with like
Sip and going and
excuse me reading the file you know
trying to find some bones in a different
protocol for a change could be a really
refreshing route to take yeah I agree I
think that's that's one of the like
little kind of mini goals that I've kind
of set where I I think it would be
really cool if
um to like fuzz like a project like an
open source project and like go from
like start to finish of like having a
crash and actually like getting a full
exploit on it yeah I agree I think
that'd be really cool yeah cool um yeah
so uh next up we've got this awesome
tweet thread um from hack Luke uh this
was a couple days ago on the 13th
and uh basically he just he created a
little thread that that are some
basically 10 tips on that he recommends
on how to crush your bug bounties right
and so I think this is like really
relevant and has some awesome uh sort of
Crossing you know uh Trends and themes
that we've talked about on our podcast
in the past for sure um but you know
number one start right like I mean this
is like uh it seems it sounds obvious
right but like it's it's huge like you
have to just like take some initiative
and just like it's it seems super
overwhelming and like intimidating
um a lot of the people that I talk to
are like new hackers one of the biggest
things I hear is like decision like
fatigue right they open Hacker one they
go to the programs and there's a
thousand programs what do you pick what
do you hack on who do you you know focus
on well that's a good thing I mean
people another thing is people will jump
back and forth from from okay I need to
do
um portswiger you know Web Academy W as
whatever whatever that thing is
here's you know training thing which is
amazing and one of my top
recommendations by the way to bug crowd
University to hacker 101 to you know
nahom sex channel to Insider phd's
Channel and they just jump around and
that's great and you absolutely need to
consume that material but you can't do
that forever sometimes you got to get
you got to get in the situation you got
to get your hands dirty you got to make
a bunch of mistakes and waste a bunch of
time that should be your goal like I you
can't be afraid of that like you gotta
get in there and say like all right for
every hour I waste right now trying to
hack this or you know not finding
anything that's another hour that I'm
not gonna have to spend before I find my
my own vulnerability and to be honest
like that sounds like a bunch of BS but
I promise you that will that will
provide you value in the long run yeah
um so I really like that and the reason
why I threw this on the dock for this
time was um
yeah you know we get this question is
the number one question we get and this
podcast is not super oriented towards
beginners um we may do a beginners
episode at some point but the number one
dm that we both get is like Hey how do I
start invoke bounties how can I do bug
bounties and um and so this is a great
place to to look at for any of you that
are are getting ready to start the
process
um read through these and and take a
look at hack Luke's other content
because yeah this is a good a good path
to get rolling yeah well and and I think
what you talked about is a is a great
strategy just generally speaking but
also like especially for bug Bounty bug
Bounty is not one of those things that's
guaranteed right and we've talked about
this a lot where you can spend hours
days weeks and not find something that
you would consider you know even high
enough to submit and I think it's
important to set those kind of like
check marks or checkpoints or whatever
like set yourself some boundaries in
terms of okay
write it down if I hack for eight hours
today and I find nothing then I'm gonna
do something else or I'm gonna take this
action or you know plan ahead and write
it down so that you can sort of frame
your your your mind looking forward so
that when you hit that point you're not
like all right now what right because
we've already made a plan for it and
that'll help you feel like less lost and
less like like you haven't accomplished
stuff yeah for sure man I think we and
we've got it in the ideas doc but I
think we should definitely do a brain
hacks episode of critical thinking just
kind of talking about some of the brain
hacks that you need to be able to
survive the bug Bounty industry because
it's really it's really stressful man
and it's hard you know it's a it's a
results for you know results for money
sort of situation which is always
stressful and it's uh you know it's it's
a high fomo situation it's a high
imposter syndrome situation so there's a
lot of mental toughness that you need to
develop which I've had the opportunity
to benefit from you know being around
some of the people that have you know
gone before me and taught me some of
these things at the live hacking events
but not everyone gets that opportunity
and so I think we ought to I think maybe
we'll bump that to the to the top of the
list for our upcoming episodes because I
think that could be really of some value
yeah yeah that's a good one cool uh let
me just run through the rest of these
these real quick um number two targeting
fresh programs like we talked about it's
like you know how do you pick somewhere
to hack look for new scope stuff that
have people haven't touched that's going
to be more ripe for easy findings and
all that kind of stuff where I just
found that bug today yeah exactly focus
on your strengths right so this is like
if you want to find something you want
that satisfaction don't be like
you know oh let me learn the about
mobile for the first time and like yeah
you know you might find a phone that way
but like if you know how to web hack
just do some web hacking it's going to
be easier you're going to have less
Nuance unless you're not gonna have to
be going back and Googling all this
stuff so much it'll be a lot easier yeah
and and so just just I'll jump in and
comment on that one while we're here so
I I definitely agree with this but I
agree with this more for the beginners
of hacking right like and if you're a
web dev you should find web phones if
you're a mobile Dev you should find
mobile phones
um you know if and we've talked about
this in the past as well if you can hack
a product that you use you know hack a
product that you are actively using as
user um and you'll find you'll find that
things will go a lot easier for you all
right continue sorry for sure no no no
absolutely I appreciate the input number
four Autumn use automation wisely we
have a whole episode about this like
when to automate and like where to draw
that line and I totally agree with hack
Luke before you know if you want to save
yourself some time like you can automate
stuff but you have to be aware that it
can often lead to you know false
positives fake findings all that kind of
stuff so you really need to supplement
it in there to save yourself some time
but don't waste your time by then having
to check all those results like it
double check it and trust and not trust
it and all that kind of stuff or modify
the script time and time again like I
was talking about at the beginning of
the episode you know it definitely
becomes uh a thing you know and I've
recently also I I used to be a just my
own tool sort of guy like I ran besides
stuff like you know Mass DNS which I'm
not going to go write everything in a
low-level language and stuff like that I
would mostly use my own tools designed
the way that I wanted them and that sort
of thing but lately I've really gained
an appreciation for uh specifically
project Discovery tools with httpx and
dnsx and just essentially very
um Linux
um what is Linux I can't think of the
word in English that I'm trying to say
the the form the flow of how Linux does
it right flow of those tools you know
where you can pipe stuff back you know
into other tools and the way that they
connect together
um and so I think that's that that's
really cool as well you know being able
to use other people's tools effectively
and build that into your own flow and
not always having to build your own
stuff because that definitely will
become a time a Time drain yep cool so
number five practicing on vulnerable
apps
um I think I I'm a little bit conflicted
about this one because we've had some
discussions about this I think off the
air about like yeah you know new hackers
and stuff again I have lots of friends
and and people who are getting into
hacking and they're like oh I was
spending you know a bunch of hours like
doing damn vulnerable web app or or hack
the box I'm like that's awesome but
but you should like I would encourage
you to like now that you've got like
your hands around sort of the basics and
you've got some ideas go do some real
hacking like go do some bug Bounty like
absolutely you know I I don't want to
say it's a waste of time because it's
not like it's a learning experience
right and like I think ctfs and that
type of like structured vulum that like
you know it exists you just have to
figure out how to exploit it it's great
practice however if you're really trying
to optimize your time and like use it
efficiently and get like that Real World
Experience jump into bug Bounty as soon
as you can so that you can really like
start to look at real apps and less of
these sort of setup structured
preconditioned scenarios totally agree
yeah number six read reports from other
Hunters I would put this right on par
with reading blog posts and like you
know making bookmarks and doing your own
research and all that kind of stuff it
also goes really well with the next one
which is engaging with the community I
think like staying in tune with what's
going on within both just the general
security Community as well as bug Bounty
community on Twitter on blogs
podcasts yeah the critical thinking bug
money podcast you know talking about
yeah like any of those types of methods
like the fact like shouting out our
podcast yeah
yeah yeah the fact that you're listening
to this right now like already tells you
you're already doing it right yeah
you're in there you're engaging with the
community you're reading slash listening
to reports all that kind of stuff this
is like a great way to get that kind of
first-hand Knowledge from like you know
like otherwise how are you gonna find
this stuff like you know it's it's
really really hard this is one of the
things that I think a lot of bug Benny
uh Hunters struggle with is finding this
kind of information out there like
openly and freely and in in a way that's
accessible for them to to read and
understand
yeah yeah for sure
um on so document everything we've also
that's the next one we talked about that
a little bit
um I don't do it so well but I I've
realized after we did that episode
talking about that that I uh have
actually do it a little bit more than I
thought so you know especially when I'm
leaving a Target and I'm you know
holding those uh work-life balance
boundaries really well when I say okay
you know what ding ding alarm's going
off it's 4 45 or whatever I'm gonna
spend the next 15 minutes cleaning up my
my you know uh home directory and uh and
documenting all my stuff and you know
knowing where I left off brain dumping
my attack vectors and that sort of thing
and I think also working with you in the
last event
made us do that a little bit better too
we uh we got our own little um hack MD
dot IO
um notes up and we're dumping dumping
sort of potential leads in there so I
think that was I think that was really
good
um but it's definitely not something
that I I don't know I wouldn't put that
in like the top uh maybe it makes the
top ten you know it makes the top ten
yeah yeah I mean I was gonna say the
same thing is this is something I'm I'm
not the greatest at and haven't been the
greatest at historically but starting
since like the last event I've been
getting better at it and I think finding
a good system whether that's heck MD or
something else to to like help you
structure notes in in a way where it's
it's not quite brain dumping but it's
more it's a little more organized right
yeah and like some way to structure that
brain dumb I think I've seen a couple
tools I can't remember what they are but
hack MD was really like the first one
that comes to mind and I think something
like that is a great idea even if it's
just local markdown files yeah not hack
MD but like whatever you want to do to
just take notes so that you have some
place you can search and reference back
is a great idea yeah my brain just
automatically writes marked down anyway
I can't even use Google Docs anymore it
just has to be marked down yeah
um so be persistent and enjoy the
process of the last two and that's
that's something that I kind of wanted
to talk about recently because I I do
get out like I mentioned before I do get
all these messages on like Hey how do I
do this what should I do how do I hack I
had a conversation with a guy I'll give
him a shout out here if I can find his
name uh yeah it's Prince ox
and I was talking to this person and
they were saying hey you know should I
pivot to a different program you know
tell me exactly what to do and this is
what I told them I told him hey go to
your target
spend four hours using the application
and writing down every single attack
Factor you can think of in as my my new
detail as you can possibly think of then
go back and test every single one of
those very thoroughly think about when
you think you've tested it
think about it again and make sure you
you have tested it properly from every
single angle and he did that and he
found some bugs and I was really happy
to see that
um and and then he said hey you know I
found some bugs but to be honest I feel
like I'm getting through you know
everything that I can find you know on
this Target and I said that's perfect
that's where you want to be now answer
me this do you know that API better than
any other bug Bounty Hunter do you know
that API better than the devs that wrote
that API no then stay stay there do not
pivot just yet because really the way
the way you you get some of these crazy
villains is is by becoming a mega expert
on these things you should see some of
the guys
um
I won't shout them out specifically
because I'm not sure how how much
information about their flow they want
to give out but like some of the top
hackers on very singular programs you
know you go and see them and they have
literally built full applications around
documenting the API and how the you know
authorization structure works on these
applications so they literally have
built an application to help them
document the application of their target
like that's the kind of badass like I'm
totally addicted to this like you know
concentration that you need to find
crazy bugs and destroy a Target so
um definitely agree with with Luke's
topic here on being persistent and yeah
enjoying the process that's another
thing is just being naturally curious
not stressing too much about hey am I
finding well am I not finding volumes
but trusting the process and enjoying it
along the way and you'll have better
results that way for sure yeah yeah that
persistence thing that's something we've
we've talked about and I couldn't agree
more like deep dive like go deep as deep
as you possibly can because that's where
you're going to start to make some of
those like key connections like in your
brain like oh I wonder if this thing is
accessible through this other endpoint
or whatever and and finding those hidden
endpoints in the JavaScript or or in the
mobile app or whatever like you know
figuring out different ways to to map
that API as good as a developer can I
think that that's like really one of
those those key those key things that
makes a difference between like the
number one on the program and the number
three four five
totally agree man
um Okay cool so definitely check out uh
hack Luke's uh Twitter thread we'll
we'll put it in the description yeah the
next one that I wanted to talk about is
a link tweeted out by mokusal
um milk so4 on Twitter
um and he tweeted out a link to asset
note uh an article that they published
recently on bypassing IIs authorization
I love the title you know you definitely
know shoves just went to Google it's
like how to write a clickbaity title
bypass ISS authorization with this one
weird trick like I love it
um and and he got three RCS so you know
for for what he can't he can't do in
clickbaity titles he I definitely can do
with the hacking
um no but this this this write-up is
like a uh is a masterpiece man
um I was just talking to Joel about it
before that episode
um just stunning and I'm really glad
that it popped up
today and I'm actually glad we put it at
the end of our uh actually so you
actually also had something else you
want to talk about right Shadow clone so
let's let's go let's go jump to that
first and then we'll come back to this
blog by acid note because
um I I want to talk to that in the
context of the the source code review
stuff that we're going to do after that
yeah for sure yeah so we yeah it's
basically you know to to a double whammy
both from shoves here
um infosec Au uh and so shobs tweeted
out a couple weeks ago maybe like two
and a half weeks ago at the end of April
uh that he had spent a couple hours uh
you know working with this tool called
Shadow clone
um and he said that you know once you
get everything set up and you get your
python M matching the runtime Python and
everything basically Works outside of
the box and you can use https which is a
tool that we've talked about before
product Discovery yeah yeah 100 really
awesome tool to scale your scanning out
across you know a ton of different
instances and he said he did 150 000 sub
domains in three to four minutes um
that's wow pretty awesome
and if you look at this this project
it's called Shadow clone
um and I had never heard of this until
uh shubs tweeted it out but essentially
it's inspired and very similar to Axiom
and fleeks which are two other kind of
like distributed
um you know VPS type like task running
solutions that exist but the big
difference at least that's claimed
Within These docs I haven't tested this
myself is that one you can have like 10
times more instances up to a thousand
instances it's mostly free uh compared
to essentially pricing per instance and
per minute uh with Axiom and it's faster
and it's basically free like nice
there's no idle cost yeah so I may have
said I may have said this mostly for you
twice we're emphasizing that that point
very good again mostly free yes so
that's what it literally says in the
docs too mostly free mostly free yes and
and the mostly is like you know
technically there are limits like in the
Millions on how many like calls you can
make but the way that this works is it
uses um these uh these these Dynamic
like serverless functions to run your
tasks so it'll take your input file
it'll split it line by line and then
it'll run like it'll distribute it among
a bunch of different instances and it's
uses like free tier instances and all
that kind of stuff so it basically costs
nothing again and uh yeah I mean it
seems really really awesome kind of
similar to
um fire procs which we were talking
about uh maybe a week or two ago that is
kind of like this but just for like the
request side where it does it puts it
through an API Gateway so I think this
is a really awesome tool it's certainly
more flexible than the fireproc stuff
that we talked about
um and I think it's a really awesome way
to you know distribute your scanning so
you're not taking down taking down
Services I really I really like that it
supports the different it supports
Google AWS and Azure too um I think
that's that's pretty rad yeah that's
awesome all right cool
um
let me just actually I'm just going to
get clone this down right now before I
forget because I'm gonna I'm gonna
forget if I don't do it
um okay cool
so yeah going back to what I was talking
about before
um like you said double special today
for for shoves killing it always with
the content
um so yeah the reason why I wanted to
butt this right up to our conversation
about
um about uh source code review is
because it's pretty much a master class
in source code review
um and I think this just reinforces the
point that that
um that hack Luke made in in the in the
post of just making sure you're
religiously reading
um the post by respected hackers uh you
know that you that you admire and shubs
is is the top of that list for me he
really is
um and so you know and this this extends
not only not only to people that are
trying to learn or get into the space
but also to top hackers we have to stay
on top of this stuff and continue
reading and it just becomes sort of a
memory you know a muscle reflex now
every anytime I see anything like this
come out that I've got to get through it
so the list I was get kind of long and
overwhelming sometimes but once you get
into it it's really it's really valuable
okay so last week we talked a little bit
about
um vs code and and how to use it and
that sort of thing and we we addressed
some of the stuff that we wanted to get
to with source code uh review but we uh
like we talked about how to get access
to source code we talked about you know
Docker containers npm libraries
um you know leaks on GitHub uh you know
trying to get free trials of software
um and now you've got the source code
you know maybe you pull it from an lfd
maybe you do one of those things but
what do you do with the source code
after you've gotten it so that's what we
want to spend some time talking about
today
um
and uh this article by by shubs
um I think outlines a really good flow
and let me just kind of break that down
for us real quick let me let me let me
get some water before I do that because
I might think it's gonna yeah no and I
just wanted to Echo like a master class
might even be under understating it just
because like I don't think if I were to
tell somebody like how to do source code
review it would be much better than what
Chubbs is doing here because jobs is
doing like exactly the types of stuff
that we're talking about in terms of how
to analyze like what you're dealing with
how to figure out a tax surface how to
figure out how stuff works all that kind
of stuff and all of the asset note blog
posts are incredibly like detailed in
depth really walking you through like
how they're thinking about it how
they're the tools they're using
mentality like all of it right and so
like that type of insight is really
really useful
um and yeah I I mean seriously go go
read it but I'll let you yeah let's
let's like walk through so all right
cool so we'll walk through this but
first Joel I want you to tell the people
what is a source what is a sink because
those two terms are very important to
this flow and a I think they're the two
most important Concepts in in source
code review yeah so a source and a sync
right so it it might be kind of
straightforward if you think about it
but a source is where you're starting
and a sync is where you're ending and so
in source code what that really means is
a source is something like an input
parameter or maybe a request Handler
would be your Source function and then
the sync is going to be the function
that returns a response to the HTTP
server or maybe a database a database
execute call or a cursor execution or a
query something right yeah that's you're
saying so basically starting from some
place some path syncing in another place
right so when we do source code review
um the reason sources instincts are
really important is because they're the
two best places to to start from so
you've got two prime primary paths that
you can go right you can start at a sync
and say okay I want to be able to
control data getting passed into this
function
and so for a great example of a good
sync would be the python exec function
or the python sub process
P open function or execute functions in
C and and you know just think about any
like any sort of template injection you
know any anytime you're dealing with a
place that you would want to inject to
cause a file right you know for example
those would all be great examples of of
um of syncs so you've identified these
places where you want to get your data
the reason why you want to get that your
data there is because you can pivot and
gain greater access control right so for
example
if we were able to go after the sync P
open and we can get uh in Python then we
may be able to get our our malicious
input in there and then we could execute
system level commands which allow us to
Shell the the server and so that's
that's uh that's a great example of a of
a sink now a source like like you said
Joel you know it that's that's where
we're getting our user data coming in
right
um and this is another popular place to
start from so you can either start with
the same kid work backwards to the
source or you can start at the source
and work work forward to the sync
um Joel which one do you if you had to
pick I know that we we both do both but
if you had to pick one which one do you
think is like
the one the way to go with so personally
I like starting with sinks
um but like you said like you have to do
both because starting with sinks can be
really great but it's also very
frustrating if you keep tracing them
back and there's no source and you don't
know what your sources would look like
so
understanding what where the sinks are
and like finding them can also be a
challenge because it's like an unknown
number of sinks right like there's
infinite possibilities could depend on
the application yeah we just we just did
a source code review where the target uh
used calls to the command line a lot
um and unfortunately they encapsulated
all of that into one function and that
function was Secure but if we hadn't
known about that that sync if we hadn't
um you know tracked down that sink and
then sort of traced it back then we
wouldn't have been able to audit all the
paths and actually at the end of the day
Joe we actually did find one
vulnerability that got paid out using
that so I feel pretty good about that
that's true um but yeah so I really like
that point is that one of the tricky
Parts about syncs is there's not like
and there are some lists out there it's
like all right here the sinks for PHP or
whatever but they're not all going to be
the same all the time
um and so getting to know your sinks in
the application could be a really good
exercise in source code review yeah and
then like you said like
take your sinks understand sort of how
they work how they're structured where
they might be living within the code
base and then try and figure out your
sources so like where are HTTP functions
being handled where like what is where
does inbound data come in and then see
if there's any way to connect it to do
they ever interact is there any sort of
middle Frameworks where they might be
talking with each other are there any
ways that you could maybe use some
open-ended side of the application
Behavior to get your way over to that
sync and just like trying to identify
any way to connect those two
I think it's really hard to go like
completely from one to the other
um without like doing a little bit of
both yeah for sure man I totally agree
and but I will say I am in the opposite
vote if I had to pick one I would start
with sources and the reason for that is
because
um a lot of times syncs have to do with
stuff like
um rce or command injection or file
arbitrary file right or configuration
file injection which we'll talk about
soon
um fun fun vulnerability there
um but uh they don't necessarily always
include business logic stuff
um and so and those are still relevant
to the application even though we are a
lot of times in a routing source code
we're going for the prize we're trying
to get rce you know trying to find
deserialization or some of those other
bugs I mentioned
um but I think tracing the sources
allows me to understand the application
a lot better when I'm first getting into
it so
um I often start with identifying all
the places where I can trigger something
in the application to happen and then
I'll sort of Trace those down the paths
and try to map out
um you know where what sort of logic
flow it has what if statements what
functions are being called and and then
use that to understand the application
and then once I sort of understand the
application having mapped out a lot of
those paths then I can kind of say okay
well maybe I've got the sync and then
maybe I can work backwards from there
but if I had to pick one of the two I
think I would start with start with the
sources yeah yeah and I think like that
approach is also like completely
reasonable because for sure
understanding your attack surface is
highly important right it's just like
like you don't have to go from the sinks
if anything you know going from the
sources probably makes a little more
sense because you're hunting for things
that you know are reachable and you're
at least able to understand like where
your data is going from The Edge inwards
versus trying to find some way out from
deep within right and so yeah yeah I
think like it just depends on maybe what
you're looking for or or you know what
your time constraints are or if you have
a ton of syncs it might not make sense
to go through every single one it might
be easier to just start with the sources
and yeah so sources starting with the
sources definitely takes more time I
think if you're trying to find a quick
rce or a quick bug then it might be best
to work from syncs backwards but then if
you start from sources you can also try
to find areas where authorization breaks
down and have business logic impact so I
think that's I think that's yeah another
another cool route like you said okay so
the way that I wanted to sort of uh so I
wanted to break that down for for y'all
just kind of have that conversation make
sure we understand the terminology of
sources and syncs quick editors note
before we get into the next section the
article that we're talking about was
released by assetnode which is a company
owned by shubs but the actual author of
the article was an asset known employee
by the name of Dylan Pinder uh Dylan is
also tremendously skilled I've heard
shubs talk about him in the past so uh
sorry from the misattribution Dylan
great work on the write-up and great
work on the bug all right cool with that
cleared up back to the show and then I
also kind of wanted to talk about how
this correlates to shubs is write up and
how he actually uses one of my main
tricks for it's not really a trick it's
just how you find into stuff
to find sources and what he does uh you
know if you look in the reconnaissance
section of the write-up
um he he one of the first things he does
is he looks at I'm trying to find all
the files that he can access and then he
says unfortunately we couldn't find much
of them and so then he goes and looks in
the web.config file which shows the
routing for the application so this is
an extremely important piece you have to
understand how your application well
actually we can even take a step back
right Joel we can say uh not even
routing at this point what services are
running on the application right what
are on the on the target you know you
might be you might be interacting with
an iot device you might be interacting
with something else but um what kind of
services are running are there internal
Services running behind a reverse proxy
are there are there Services running on
on different ports that you can't even
hit from you know various interfaces
that you could use to Pivot having an
understanding of that flow I think is
extremely important
um and that should be the first place to
start and then once you identify the
services you can get into routes and
stuff like that yeah for sure I think
like this is one of the best approaches
because you're starting from like the
very beginning right you're looking at
the configuration file very good place
to start yeah from the very beginning
it's all right I went all like nursery
rhyme mode there go ahead sorry
yeah so I I just think like configs are
a great place to start you know because
like how does it work how is it
configured right and yeah go from there
that's a great source of Truth yeah for
sure so so what he does here is he he
takes a look at the web config file on
the sitecore config file and he finds
the ways that various requests are being
routed
um and what kind of paths you can hit in
the application
and then you know he mentions it's a
little bit further down let's see if I
can find it in the in the write-up but
um he does an excellent job of well
we'll get to that when we get to it but
essentially bypassing an authentication
flow and actually this proves one of my
theories wrong that I was going to tell
you guys about this week but I I think
I'll change my my thought on this before
I um uh you know with with shubs right
up I would normally say
uh that you should under try to
understand the auth scheme and then
understand whether you're trying to find
auth or unauthor vulnerabilities and
then go look at the unauth scope if
you're trying to find another
vulnerabilities right but really that's
a fallacious assumption because the
further you understand the auth and how
the auth is working there then you may
be able to find bypasses like he does in
the situation so um he actually looked
at auth and unauth scope and then
figured out a way to you know sort of
get around the auth flow that the
application was implementing to access
some some functionality
um so that was that was really
impressive um and and so just to sort of
walk through this flow he looks at the
sitecore config file and the web config
file he identifies how the application
is routing various requests and then he
is taking these dll files out he's
decompiling them which with with uh DN
spy like like we mentioned um that's not
the one that you recommend right dot
yeah I recommended dot Peak dnspy is a
little bit older and I think it's
actually not in active development
anymore however it does allow you to do
debugging specifically which I think is
one of the reasons why
um the asset new team decided to use
this because you can set break points
within running apps without the source
code that's so cool you can hit those
breakpoints and make sure that like what
you think is happening is actually
happening and so that's super super
useful for for figuring out if your
exploit is working and if it's not why
not and and all that yeah I've done that
in the browser but that is actually
something I've never done and something
that I do want to do in something that
I'm reverse engineering is you know
loaded up into uh something where you
can set break points and stuff like that
and and they're they're very specific
situations where you can do this you can
do it in Java a decompiled Java and you
can do it in
um and obviously in in net here like
what they've got
um but that I think that's really cool
so then what he does is he identifies
um
this
sitecore.mvc.dll
file and he identifies how various
things are being routed he identifies
slash API core slash controller so that
this is the controller variable and
slash action so now he's got he's opened
up to himself a scope that's really
um that's really important and Joel this
is the kind of thing like what we did
with
um well I'll I'll bleep it later with
uh was when you know we found the the
endpoint where the end point we knew
that this is where we needed to get
access to functionality and then we made
it our mission to get to that that point
where we could access those routes to
open up the scope right so it's not
necessarily our hacking isn't
necessarily always focused on like how
do I get to the sync but also expanding
the scope that you can have access to
and I think that's something you did a
really good job of in the past uh event
was you you know we had it we found that
that Target that we needed to get access
to and then you were able to find a way
to get access to that which expanded our
scope so much allowed us to text so test
so much more
um source code and uh and really opened
it up so um that's the same sort of
thing he's doing here he's identifying a
way to trigger different functions
within the application and then he's
being able to use that to you know sort
of weave through the application and hit
various endpoints the routing in this
application is really funky
um and so
um he uses that to eventually get RC
through leaking a file
a web config file and that file contains
the the keys for good old and operator
that we mentioned earlier his teleric
exploit which came back in 2019 which is
used all the time excellent exploit
because in that enabled him to use that
exploit because the encryption keys are
stored in the web.config file so that
resulted in RC via deserialization
um through what was really an lfd which
we talked about last time as well yeah
and just an awesome like
just like a great way to show chaining
different parts of the application
really going deep and understanding
these separate moving parts and how they
connect together and then tying it all
into one big nice putting a nice little
bow on it and handing the team this
beautiful POC that does everything all
together right yeah yeah absolutely I I
love that and then the other thing that
I wanted to
um point out and let me just go ahead
and note down what time we said the
things that we need to bleep out really
quickly because I'm definitely I hope I
don't forget to do that
um uh but yeah so the other thing that I
wanted to point out was this was behind
auth right like I mentioned before and
so what he does then is he continues to
look for a way to
um to bypass off here and uh the way
that he ends up doing that is by looking
very closely at
um the uh this dot context user identity
is authenticated check right so how is
that how is that being generated and
after deep diving into that and looking
into sort of how that functionality is
created he found that and I love this
this is such a great hack dude I just I
love it right because you know when you
have a user and it's something like is
authenticated it's like okay well I'm
gonna have to be a user at some point
not necessarily because what he finds is
that
um there's some functionality
surrounding mailing lists and uh let me
just go ahead and read the line it's a
sitecore could be configured with a
rendered a renderer user to enable a
user who is subscribing to a mail list
to access information without having to
log in when they view the email so when
they when they've clicked on the link
from their email
freaking brilliant and then when when
viewing these items I'm just going to
finish reading this when viewing items
this way the user provides some query
parameters such as EC underscore message
underscore ID and EC underscore ID which
tells psychors the details of the email
item they are viewing you know what that
freaking does that configures the user
property on the application to be the
user that the renderer user and bypasses
the is authenticated check which allows
you to access some of this functionality
and I'm just like what a masterpiece
yeah right beautiful the stars have
aligned like it's amazing that's how it
always feels you know with these things
is like wow look at this you know
alignment phenomenal so really just to
review really quickly here what shelves
does
is he looks through the routes
understands how the application is
routing understand expands his scope by
getting access to this API sitecore and
then being able to define the controller
in the actions audits the code and the
controller is in the actions finds a
sync um that we didn't really talk about
too much but was essentially a uh a
preview functionality that allowed him
to pass in a parameter which led to
local file disclosure
and use that lfd to disclose the
web.config file which contained the
encryption Keys which he could use for a
known cve by an operator himself to get
a deserialized rce and then made that a
sort of a semi-unauthenticated bug by
using abusing the is authenticated check
which can be sort of uh spoofed by
subscribing to a mail list and then
clicking a link from the mail list which
will generate these EC message
parameters that can be used to get your
is authenticated your current user
authenticated user to be rendered a
renderer user rather than just no user
right
yeah crazy like just like an amazing
like combination of of different bugs
and different like pieces of knowledge
throughout the application and just just
well done to the Sno team incredible
amazing route so route expansion or
route you know understanding the routes
expanding your scope
finding your your sink
um those are those are some major some
major pieces of this uh some major
takeaways from this this article you
know the the flow that he had there so
anyway really cool that that came up
that this week when we were wanting to
talk about that
um the source is in syncs thing
um and we we spent a lot of time already
talking about doing an in-depth talk on
a vulnerability
um so I think we'll save any any report
summarization for next time if that
works for you Joel yeah yeah I think
that's all good okay sweet all right
we'll call it there all right sounds
good that's the Pod peace
yo
um I've recorded this outro so many
times this one's gonna be the last one I
I'm done
um if you enjoyed the episode please
head over to YouTube uh find our Channel
at critical thinking podcast and drop us
to subscribe also on your podcast app of
choice just just subscribe please and we
don't want you to miss an episode we
want to keep hanging out
um finally if you could tell someone
about the podcast that would be amazing
that would make my day tell your tell
your friend tell your weird neighbor
tell your hacker chats tell anyone who
listens go to chatgpt and tell chat gbt
about critical thinking bug bunny
podcast
all right guys we'll see you next week
after having so much fun recording these
outros I figured I'd throw a couple
bloopers in for y'all at the end enjoy
um and drop a like subscribe whatever
there hack hack hack
yo thanks for listening to this episode
of critical thinking bug Bounty podcast
if you enjoyed head over to YouTube and
drop a like And subscribe and also
subscribe on your YouTube nope
laughs
[Music]